Ibragim Zubailov

+385 (68) 458-679 | Bar, Montenegro | vulgarnykarlson@gmail.com | telegram: vulgarnykarlson linkedin.com/in/vulgarnykarlson | github.com/vulgarnykarlson | gitlab.karlson.dev/individual

SKILLS

Golang, Typescript, NodeJS, NestJS, REST, WebSockets, GRPC, GraphQL, Web3(Blockchains:Bitcoin,Ethereum) MySQL, Postgres, Clickhouse, Redis, Aerospike, Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS GlusterFS, ElasticSearch, Ansible, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Software engineer and leader with a 7 years of experience, with strong fundamentals in NodeJS, Golang, Architecture and Database knowledge. History of my work is covered industries as Adtech (OpenRTB), Storage and Web3 systems.

My expertise in handling high-load systems has provided me with the knowledge to craft optimal application architecture, conduct A/B testing, and transition from monolithic to microservice systems, catering to both business requirements and overall team efficiency.

I've consistently analyzed every aspect of third-party technology implementation, risk assessment, transition phases, and understanding the benefits derived from their usage.

WORK EXPERIENCE (6.5 YEARS)

MTS Group Senior Golang and NodeJS Developer

 $\begin{array}{c} Moscow,\ Russia\\ {\rm Jun\ 2022--\ Jun\ 2023} \end{array}$

- Develop high-load b2b storage. stack: Golang, NodeJS, Kafka, Clickhouse, RabbitMQ
- Service for optimizing load-balance of storage throughput. stack: golang, glusterfs
- Optimized retrieve data from storage. stack: golang, clickhouse

Lofty Teamlead (8 backend)

Moscow, Russia
May 2020 — May 2022

- Developed arbitrage project between advertisers(DSP) and supply platforms (SSP). Actively participated in strategizing business logic development. After 2 years project was generating over 1mil\$ revenue, and having 500k rps. stack: Golang, Aerospike, Kafka, Clickhouse, Postgres, GRPC.
- Processes added to the team: KPI performance review, roadmap planning, mentoring, idea submission point, task decoupling.
- Developed traffic quality evaluation system to predict prices for SSP
- Developed filter system to screen out fraudulent and low-quality traffic.

Techlead (4 backend)

Oct 2019 — May 2020

- Rewrited main application to achieve: stability(no fires), 3x perfomance, A/B Bussiness testing, unit/integration tests, low entry threshold(for newcomers). In 2y growed from 15k to 150k rps.. stack: NodeJS,Clickhouse,Postgres,Redis,Kafka.
- Introduced Agile pipeline
- Actively involved in the recruitment process
- Participated in architecture design including devop's and database storage parts.

Senior NodeJS Developer

 $Jul \ 2019 - Oct \ 2019$

- Develop high-load (70k rps) push advertisement sender, with a big flexibility of settings. stack: NodeJS, MySQL, RabbitMQ
- Micro-service for authorization

Belsona Investment Group Middle NodeJS Developer

Moscow, Russia Jun 2017 — Jul 2019

- Develop arbitrage bot between blockchain smart-contract and exchange (Binance/Bitfinex). stack: NodeJS,MySQL,Typescript, Web3(Ethereum), Websockets.
- Design and develop risk evaluation system and a predictive model based on market trends, trading data, blockchain activities.
- Automation scripts for reducing routine tasks, specifically for ICO projects
- Devised service for risk score ICO products.

EDUCATION